Ryan J. Skelly

Portsmouth, RI & Durham, NH

ryan@iatek.com, ryanskelly.com, linkedin.com/in/ryan-j-skelly/, (401) 864-5571

Profile:

I am an outgoing, hardworking, and determined individual. From a young age, I've always been interested in the Software Development field. My natural intuition and years of practice have served me well at my current employer, the UNH IOL. Abstraction and critical thinking help me solve development and network-related roadblocks I encounter. I also have experience coding in both a front and backend context, along with Industry-Standard Libraries and Frameworks. My recent interests include Kubernetes, Docker, Virtualization, DevSecOps, and Cloud Infrastructure. I am graduating from the University of New Hampshire (May 2023) with a B.S. in Information Technology with a minor in Analytics.

Education:

- University Of New Hampshire (2019-2023)
 B.S. Information Technology, Analytics Minor
- Portsmouth High School (2015-2019)

Skills:

- Web Development

HTML/XML
 CSS
 Bootstrap
 DBMS
 Apache2/Httpd
 Typescript/ReactJS
 Bootstrap
 REST, GraphQL &
 SOAP APIs

- Networking

- IPv4 & v6 Protocols
 - Device/Network
 - Configuration
 - Network Admin.
 - Server Management
 - Monitoring
 - Poster Continuo

- Packet Capture- Routing, Switching,Analysis- Routing, Switching,Service Hardening

- Software Development

- Python- C/C++- SQL/MySQL- Java+Maven

- CI/CD & Cloud Management

- AWS- Azure- GCP- Unit/TDD- Atlassian- Gitlab

Experience:

InterOperability Laboratory (2020-Present)
 Test Technician & Software Developer

I began testing network devices for IPv6 Ready Logo and USGv6 certifications at the IOL. While working as a technician, I was responsible for analyzing network traffic, installing and managing vendors' devices (both Physical and Virtual), giving progress reports to vendors, and leveraging scripts to automate testing. After a year and a half of experience, I was chosen by the IP staff to move on from my technician duties and work as a script developer. As a script developer, I was tasked to fix bugs and write test scripts for the IOL's INTACT software package. While in both roles, I operated in an agile setting and used various versioning and software management platforms.

- Aquidneck Pizza (2019-2020)
 Pizza Delivery, Gen. Assistant
- 15 Point Rd Restaurant (2016-2019) Busser

Projects & Awards:

IOL Star Award (Spring 2022)
Senior Capstone - Enterprise VPN Solution(OrionVPN)
IT 502 Final - TRH Design Website
IT 725 White Paper - Multiplexed Stream Delivery in HTTP/1.1,
HTTP/2, and HTTP/3
Project Management Web App - ReactJS